<anime id="5625" restricted="false">
<type>TV Series</type>
<episodecount>26</episodecount>
<startdate>2008-04-04</startdate>
<enddate>2008-09-26</enddate>
<titles>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="main">To Love-Ru: Trouble</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="synonym">とらぶる</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="synonym">To-Love-Ru</title>
<title xml:lang="ru" type="synonym">Любовный переполох</title>
<title xml:lang="ru" type="synonym">Любовь и прочие неприятности</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="synonym">To LOVE Ru - Trouble</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="synonym">Trouble</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="synonym">toloveru</title>
<title xml:lang="zh-Hans" type="synonym">出包王女</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="short">tlr</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="official">To LOVEる -とらぶる-</title>
<title xml:lang="en" type="official">To Loveru</title>
<title xml:lang="ko" type="official">To LOVE루 -트러블-</title>
</titles>
<relatedanime>
<anime id="6463" type="Sequel">To Love-Ru: Trouble (2009)</anime>
</relatedanime>
<similaranime>
<anime id="377" approval="42" total="56">Urusei Yatsura</anime>
<anime id="8719" approval="40" total="69">Haiyore! Nyaruko-san</anime>
<anime id="1805" approval="22" total="30">Girls Bravo: First Season</anime>
<anime id="9459" approval="13" total="25">Haiyore! Nyaruko-san W</anime>
<anime id="10529" approval="9" total="15">Shinmai Maou no Testament</anime>
<anime id="4821" approval="5" total="13">Seto no Hanayome</anime>
<anime id="5578" approval="5" total="10">Kemeko Deluxe!</anime>
<anime id="193" approval="3" total="8">Ranma 1/2 Nettou Hen</anime>
<anime id="368" approval="3" total="8">Ranma 1/2: Kessen Tougenkyou! Hanayome o Torimodose!</anime>
<anime id="160" approval="3" total="3">UFO Princess Valkyrie</anime>
<anime id="9903" approval="2" total="10">Nisekoi</anime>
<anime id="4576" approval="2" total="8">Ranma 1/2</anime>
<anime id="8620" approval="1" total="4">Ano Natsu de Matteru</anime>
</similaranime>
<recommendations total="19">
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="453807">I guess you should be satisfied with 26 eps full of echii</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="53340">When I see this anime, automatically I think in urusei yatsura... very similar plot but, replace ataru with a shy and unlucky boy, and you obtain this anime... very funny, an easy to see, if you like fan service this a a good anime for you</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="748358">Mixed feelings. You get a lovable, heartwarming, but airheaded, main female character and your classic empty and plain drone of a male lead. Through all the episodes, ecchi was well integrated into the plot and the subsequent slapstick humor is guaranteed to keep you entertained. The anime is very successful in that aspect, and I liked it. However, it is way from perfect. Every episode or so gets a new character introduction, and while some of them are interesting, others are just stereotypical, clichéd drones who are the protagonists of their filler episodes. Speaking of filler, this anime is full of it, and there are arcs that it is best to skip. The following seasons, including the Darkness seasons, repeat the exact same formula, and also contain a lot of filler, albeit with new characters, again, some good, other just clichéd husks. In short, if you like heartwarming and ecchi, but also repetitive and unimaginative series, the 80-episode To Love Ru saga is a good choice.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="100670">A lot of ecchi, a cute main character with an unusual peronality.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="194504">It was an okay watch overall, though first half alot better than the second one. I enjoyed the progressing-comedy-story, it was good. But have to keep in mind that episodes 14-23 are basically fillers. You could throw them out the window and would not miss anyting much. TL;DR: if you like (lots of) nudity, ecchi and comedy, this may be a decent watch for you.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="533215">i really think is a good anime even if the last episode didn`t surprise me at all.. i was every time laughing :D</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="292982">This is fun</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="246927">I`ll be frank there is a deep meaningful story in the series and the ones that don`t get that are either retarded or unable to read. I will not spoil it but I will say that it is more than just a typical Ecchi anime. And for those who complains about this being a Harem anime and shit might want to read the tag lines you fucking idiots, if you don`t like those tags don`t watch it, simple as that! The only thing I can say that I don`t like about this anime is that it`s too short it feels almost `rushed`, also these generic characters maybe won`t suit everybody but they did a good job in keeping them in their element holding on to their personality etc. The story pacing might be too slow for some but I felt it going quite smoothly. Anyways this series comes to show that story is equally important as character development and personality that you grow to care about or connect to in some way and this series delivers that.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="789094">Lolis checked , Milf checked , comedy checked , blackholeless checked You still want more? To me it is like merging things in Doraemon+Fanservice</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="237531">WERE ARE YOU WAITING FOR!!!!</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="301442">Entertaining afternoon watch with lots of fanservice</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="453453">Amazing</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Must See" uid="235338">A must see anime, especially for those who like to watch a harem, ecchi, comedy, kawaii type of anime. You will never get bored watching this.</recommendation>
</recommendations>
<url>http://www.tbs.co.jp/anime/to-love-ru/</url>
<creators>
<name id="682" type="Direction">Kato Takao</name>
<name id="719" type="Animation Work">Xebec</name>
<name id="2971" type="Music">Watanabe Takeshi</name>
<name id="2985" type="Original Work">Yabuki Kentarou</name>
<name id="3467" type="Series Composition">Yamatoya Akatsuki</name>
<name id="9087" type="Chief Animation Direction">Oka Yuuichi</name>
<name id="9086" type="Original Work">Hasemi Saki</name>
<name id="9087" type="Character Design">Oka Yuuichi</name>
</creators>
<description>* Based on a shounen manga written by http://anidb.net/cr9086 [Hasemi Saki] and illustrated by http://anidb.net/cr2985 [Yabuki Kentarou], serialised in http://anidb.net/cr5372 [Weekly Shounen Jump]. High school boy http://anidb.net/ch2354 [Yuuki Rito] is too shy to confess to the girl of his dreams, http://anidb.net/ch2358 [Sairenji Haruna]. One day after coming home and sulking in the bath, a mysterious nude girl appears out of nowhere. Her name is http://anidb.net/ch2355 [Lala] and she comes from the planet Deviluke, where she is the heir to the throne. Her father wants her to return to her home planet so she can marry one of the husband candidates, but she decides that she wants to marry Rito in order to stay on Earth. Commander http://anidb.net/ch2372 [Zastin] has been ordered to bring Lala back and has already battled Rito. He reports to the emperor that Rito would be suited to marry Lala, after hearing Rito say that marriage is impossible unless it is with the person you love (Rito was actually defending himself, but Zastin and Lala thought he was defending Lala). With this speech, Lala truly falls in love with Rito and decides that she wants to marry Rito. Her father decides that, if Rito is able to protect Lala from her fiancés, then he can be her fiancé, but if Rito cannot do so, Lala`s father will kill Rito and destroy Earth. Note: The DVD content differs from the TV content in terms of censoring. The fog has been lifted.</description>
<ratings>
<permanent count="4472">4.56</permanent>
<temporary count="4544">6.83</temporary>
<review count="5">6.93</review>
</ratings>
<picture>21280.jpg</picture>
<resources>
<resource type="1">
<externalentity>
<identifier>9091</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="2">
<externalentity>
<identifier>3455</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="3">
<externalentity>
<identifier>4219</identifier>
<identifier>jcwbwk</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="4">
<externalentity>
<url>http://www.tbs.co.jp/anime/to-love-ru/</url>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="6">
<externalentity>
<identifier>To_love_ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="7">
<externalentity>
<identifier>To_LOVEる_-とらぶる-</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="8">
<externalentity>
<identifier>1352</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="9">
<externalentity>
<identifier>330148</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="14">
<externalentity>
<identifier>3424</identifier>
<identifier>v</identifier>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<identifier>2061</identifier>
<identifier>v</identifier>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<identifier>2062</identifier>
<identifier>v</identifier>
</externalentity>
<externalentity>
<identifier>4203</identifier>
<identifier>v</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
<tags>
<tag id="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>maintenance tags</name>
<description>These tags are used for maintenance.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="36" parentid="2607" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-01-21">
<name>military</name>
<description>The military, also known as the armed forces, are forces authorized and legally entitled to use deadly force so as to support the interests of the state and its citizens. The task of the military is usually defined as defence of the state and its citizens and the prosecution of war against foreign powers. The military may also have additional functions within a society, including construction, emergency services, social ceremonies, and guarding critical areas. Source: Wikipedia</description>
<picurl>212184.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="760" parentid="2274" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-10-04">
<name>robot helper</name>
<description>In a http://anidb.net/t2846 [science fiction] setting, the robot helper is, in a comedic sense, pretty much equivalent to what the "cute comic relief http://anidb.net/t1835 [animal sidekick]" is in a fantasy setting. The usually small machine has artificial intelligence, enabling it to support their owner / master with advice or help with menial tasks. http://anidb.net/t1278 [Androids] should not be considered robot helpers since these are far more complex; use the android tag instead.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="798" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-08-04">
<name>moe</name>
<description>Moe is a Japanese slang loanword that refers to feelings of strong affection mainly towards characters in anime, manga, and video games. Moe, however, has also gained usage to refer to feelings of affection towards any subject. Moe can be related to lust; however, pure lust without other feelings is considered outside its scope. The word Moe originated in the late 1980s and early 1990s in Japan and is of uncertain origin, although there are several theories on how it came into use. At the anime level, the http://anidb.net/t7146 [cute girls doing cute things (CGDCT)] tag may also apply. Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="922" parentid="2606" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-02-04">
<name>shounen</name>
<description>In the context of manga and associated media, shounen, literally meaning "youth" and often also specifically "boy", refers to a male audience roughly between the ages of 10 and 18. Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1136" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2019-06-18">
<name>transfer student</name>
<description>A transfer student is a student who changes from one institution or course to another at the same level. Their arrival, when not at the beginning of the school year, tends to cause a stir.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1179" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-11-21">
<name>indecisive</name>
<description>This character has trouble taking their own decisions, and may rely on others to do that instead.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1363" parentid="2856" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2019-09-21">
<name>breast fondling</name>
<description>Breast fondling is the act of touching, groping, or fondling the breasts of a person, typically female.</description>
<picurl>238325.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="1760" parentid="2608" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-05-23">
<name>bishounen</name>
<description>Young man whose beauty (and sexual appeal) transcends the boundary of gender or sexual orientation.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="1773" parentid="2608" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2019-07-12">
<name>tentacle</name>
<description>A tentacle or bothrium (plural: bothria) is one of usually two or more elongated flexible organs present in animals, especially invertebrates. Usually, Tentacles are used for feeding, feeling and grasping.</description>
<picurl>236087.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="1996" parentid="36" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-05-19">
<name>air force</name>
<description>An air force, also known in some countries as an air army or air corps, is in the broadest sense, the national military organization that primarily conducts aerial warfare. More specifically, it is the branch of a nation`s armed services that is responsible for aerial warfare as distinct from an army, navy or other branch. Typically, air forces are responsible for gaining control of the air, carrying out strategic-bombing missions and providing support to surface forces. The term "air force" may also refer to a tactical air force or numbered air force, which is an operational formation within a national air force. Air forces typically consist of a combination of fighters, bombers, helicopters, transport planes and other aircraft.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2008" parentid="2891" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-08-05">
<name>small breasts</name>
<description>This character has a bust size that is considered small. The small size is usually a bust that would use a bra which is A or B. In anime, C may rarely enter this category.</description>
<picurl>162720.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2043" parentid="2869" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-12-01">
<name>high school</name>
<description>A secondary school that usually contains grades 10 through 12 in Japan, or 9 through 12 in America.</description>
<picurl>210064.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2056" parentid="2607" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2013-09-13">
<name>cosplaying</name>
<description>This character likes to cosplay.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2202" parentid="2846" infobox="true" weight="500" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-08-12">
<name>alien</name>
<description>This entity or creature was born on another world than the main characters.</description>
<picurl>222176.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2259" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-30">
<name>naked apron</name>
<description>A character wearing nothing but an apron appears in the show.</description>
<picurl>162045.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2274" parentid="2638" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-03-30">
<name>robot</name>
<description>A robot is an automatically guided machine, able to do tasks on its own. Another common characteristic is that by its appearance or movements, a robot often conveys a sense that it has intent or agency of its own. Not to be confused with android (human-like robot).</description>
<picurl>215586.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2396" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-02-08">
<name>swimsuit</name>
<description>A swimsuit is one of several kinds of garments designed to be worn by people engaging in water-based activities or sports or during certain activities under sunlight. Most kinds of swimsuit reveal a large portion of the body surface area, but exceptions exist. The more revealing kinds may also be worn as undergarment in sports that require wetsuits, or when there is a need to display the body, as in the case of beauty pageants or bodybuilding contests. There is a very wide range of styles of modern swimsuits, which vary in relation to body coverage and materials. The choice of style of swimsuit is dependent on current fashions, community standards of modesty, and plain personal preference. Swimsuits for men usually expose the chest, while those for women do not usually do so; however, many women prefer to engage in water or sun activities with their torso uncovered, in a practice commonly described as toplessness or topfreedom. Since the early twentieth century a naturist movement has developed in western countries that seeks a return to non-sexual nakedness when swimming and during other appropriate activities; in some places around the world, nude beaches have been set aside for people who choose to engage in normal beach activities in the nude, and such beaches may or may not enforce nudity onto their goers. In anime, it is common for at least one episode to feature the characters in swimsuits, usually as an excuse for gratuitous fanservice; when that happens, the episode is usually labeled a pool or beach episode, after the place the characters went to. Swimsuits, and in particular one-piece swimsuits, are a very common fetish in Japan; while the reason for that is uncertain, a common folk explanation is the fact that boys throughout their entire adolescence are commonly exposed to their female classmates wearing them, in what might be called an experiment in sexual discovery waiting to happen.</description>
<picurl>149786.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2503" parentid="2611" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-11-30">
<name>magical girl</name>
<description>Magical girls (also known both in Japan and in the West as mahou shoujo, and in Japan as majokko) are young girls with superhuman abilities of magical nature. In the early years, magical girls usually used magic to solve everyday problems and often transformed into idols; nowadays, however, the term is most often used to refer to with girls who fight evil using magical powers, and, although transformations are still common, they tend to be more along the lines of a change of costume.</description>
<picurl>29577.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2565" parentid="2608" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-04-14">
<name>cross-dressing</name>
<description>This character sometimes wears clothes traditionally worn by and associated with the opposite sex. Cross-dressers often hide their cross-dressing identity for a long period of time and thus tend to become adept in accurately portraying the opposite sex in terms of voice, movement, behaviour, temperament, etc.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2604" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-11-08">
<name>content indicators</name>
<description>The content indicators branch is intended to be a less geographically specific tool than the `age rating` used by convention, for warning about things that might cause offence. Obviously there is still a degree of subjectivity involved, but hopefully it will prove useful for parents with delicate children, or children with delicate parents. Note: Refer to further guidance on http://wiki.anidb.net/w/Categories:Content_Indicators [the Wiki page] for how to apply tag weights for content indicators.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-28">
<name>dynamic</name>
<description>Some of the central structural elements in anime are: Plot Continuity How does the plot or several plots unfold. Are they a strictly linear retelling of one big continuing story, a serial, possibly with several side stories, or is the content chopped into a set of unconnected episodes, only sharing the same setting and characters? Stereotype Characters Then there is the question of the character set presentation. Is it completely original, or is it your usual stereotypical character cast. Both choices have their merit, for example it would not really make much sense to reinvent the wheel for a harem anime. Fans of that genre come to expect their favourite stereotype protagonists. Plot Twists Finally there is the question of how complex the plot / the story unfolds. Are there side-plots that merge into the main plot leading to unexpected plot twists, or is the anime quite predictable? The latter would not be appropriate for detective stories. In harem anime on the other hand a foreseeable outcome is actually something the fans will come to expect.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2606" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-11-05">
<name>target audience</name>
<description>Anime, like everything else in the modern world, is targeted towards specific audiences, both implicitly by the creators and overtly by the marketing. While categories are associated with specific sex and age groups, this is not a bar on the anime being enjoyed by people who don`t fit into that band; not only do crossover titles exist, but the categories also have a considerable following outside their main demographic, and a person might as well enjoy anime from all categories. Still, does not invalidate the usefulness of marking a title as one of the categories; the same themes will likely be treated differently in anime geared for different audiences. Only one should not jump the gun and assume that a title will be more or less serious or present content in this or that way due to its target audience, or conversely assume the target audience on the content and its presentation alone. As such, the audience categories help form a broad impression of how a title might work with the announced themes, but offer little to no in-depth information about specific content or its treatment. The audience categories originate from manga magazines, which group titles of a same intended audience into a magazine that is advertised as belonging to that category, and so manga-based anime will have the category from their parent work. As for anime based on other works, the audience is often debatable, but comparing information such as time slot to the manga-based anime generally helps figure out the most likely possibility. If the parent material was classified under multiple audiences over time (for example, it was originally shounen, but then as the plot changed and became more mature, it was reclassified as seinen), and the anime adapts parent material time periods covering multiple audiences, we tag all audiences covered by the anime adaptation.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-29">
<name>themes</name>
<description>Themes describe the very central elements important to the anime stories. They set the backdrop against which the protagonists must face their challenges. Be it School Life, present Daily Life, Military action, Cyberpunk, Law and Order detective work, Sports, or the Underworld. These are only but a few of the more typical backgrounds for anime plots. Add to that a Conspiracy setting with a possible tragic outcome, the Themes span most of the imaginable subject matter relevant to anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2608" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-12-04">
<name>fetishes</name>
<description>Everything under fetishes (except for Bishounen and Juujin) is strictly only meant for hentai (18 Restricted) and ecchi anime. In case of ecchi, it must be the main element of the show and not when there`s only some of it, for example, there`s some ecchi in Shinseiki Evangelion, but the fact you get to see Asuka`s pantsu doesn`t warrant it the schoolgirl fetish category. So be careful to which ecchi show you add fetishes; it`s fairly straightforward with hentai, though. Overall, this category tree is to satisfy the needs of people with different fetishes, so they can search for what tingles their tangle; hence why this is restricted to hentai and full ecchi shows. </description>
</tag>
<tag id="2609" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-09-01">
<name>original work</name>
<description>What the anime is based on! This is given as the original work credit in the OP. Mostly of academic interest, but a useful bit of info, hinting at the possible depth of story.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-04-22">
<name>setting</name>
<description>The setting describes in what time and place an anime takes place. To a certain extent it describes what you can expect from the world in the anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-08">
<name>elements</name>
<description>Next to Themes setting the backdrop for the protagonists in anime, there are the more detailed plot Elements that centre on character interactions: "What do characters do to each other or what is done to them?". Is it violent Action, an awe-inspiring Adventure in a foreign place, the gripping life of a Detective, a slapstick Comedy, an Ecchi Harem anime, a SciFi epic, or some Fantasy travelling adventure?</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2612" parentid="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>time</name>
<description>This placeholder lists different epochs in human history and more vague but important timelines such as the future, the present and the past.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2613" parentid="2610" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>place</name>
<description>The places the anime can take place in. Includes more specific places such as a country on Earth, as well as more general places such as a dystopia or a mirror world.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2624" parentid="2612" weight="500" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-02-20">
<name>present</name>
<description>Somewhere between past and future.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2627" parentid="2613" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2019-12-27">
<name>space</name>
<description>The final frontier.</description>
<picurl>242357.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2630" parentid="2613" weight="500" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-13">
<name>Earth</name>
<description>The Earth is the third planet from the Sun, and the densest and fifth-largest of the eight planets in the Solar System. It is in effect a ball of hot mud, but on the surface it`s cold enough, so most of us live on it (or are supposed to). It is circa 4.5 billion years old, and, unless we humans succeed in destroying it over the next couple of centuries, it is expected to last for quite another while, though the changes in the Sun`s emissions due to its aging will likely cause the extinction of everything; the species of earthlings are guaranteed to die, even if we fail to kill them -- unless, of course, we find ourselves another planet and figure out a way to take everything there. Our little planet on a corner of this galaxy may mean nothing in the grand scheme of things, but to its inhabitants it is their home, so, as a species, we cherish it dearly, to the point many cultures even to this day deify it. Being the home to the human civilizations, the Earth is the main setting of most fiction, be it anime or otherwise, but not only are many titles set in other places, such as unrelated fantasy worlds, in a considerable number of fictional titles the Earth is actually destroyed by aggressive alien invaders.</description>
<picurl>126792.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2638" parentid="2846" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2005-05-07">
<name>mecha</name>
<description>Mecha in Japanese basically means mechanical things; everything from an electric whisk or a car to a spaceship or a robot. Here however we limit it to the more exotic things usually referred to as mecha anime: robots, whether controlled by a human or not, and their ilk. See Androids, Piloted Robots, Power Suits, Robot Helpers, Transforming Robots for a more specific classification.</description>
<picurl>42077.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2646" parentid="2849" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-24">
<name>demon</name>
<description>In Western lore, demons are often described as minions from Hell, generally known to attack humans and feast on their flesh or possess the bodies of those with weak souls. In Eastern lore, on the other hand, they are generally supernatural, often but not always malevolent beings who can be more mischievous than actually evil, or simply supernatural spirits of no specific alignment.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2652" parentid="2853" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-01-21">
<name>super deformed</name>
<description>A caricature style often seen in anime when the character shows extreme emotions, like fear, anger, happiness, surprise, or shame. Seen as cute, as part of humorous comedy. The character`s http://anidb.net/t4055 [face suddenly turns into a simplified version], the body will usually also deform into that of a small child (oversized head, short limbs, extra-large tears).</description>
<picurl>65692.png</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2653" parentid="2853" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-04">
<name>slapstick</name>
<description>Slapstick humour is generally recognized by lots of physical abuse, horseplay and practical jokes. Also often seen are impossible situations, using sounds to illustrate impossible stunts that aren`t shown on-screen and to create tension for audience anticipation.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2655" parentid="2853" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2005-05-09">
<name>parody</name>
<description>Anime that imitate other stories (can be from TV, film, books, historical events, ...) for comic effect by exaggerating the style and changing the content of the original. Also known as spoofs. It can also refer to when whole elements of one work are lifted out of their context and reused.</description>
<picurl>150811.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2660" parentid="2627" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-15">
<name>other planet</name>
<description>The anime will fit this category if some or all of the action takes place on another planet which is supposedly in the same universe as Earth, not a complete fantasy world; usually there has to be some concept of space travel. The Latin name for Earth - Terra, would also pass the condition of being in the same universe as Earth. Basically, even mentioning of Earth existing or having existed would be enough. Although Moon is a moon, it also qualifies as Other Planet.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2661" parentid="2627" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-18">
<name>shipboard</name>
<description>Beam me up, Scotty! Space stations (think Death Star) also count. Basically, this category is to tell if the setting takes place onboard a spaceship in space. This category is not applicable if the spaceship lies on a planet and never actually gets into space.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2665" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-16">
<name>school sports festival</name>
<description>To show off the students in sports clothing — in ecchi anime the female students in particular — a sports festival (or athletic meet) is quite popular in your typical anime with school setting. Here the protagonists can show their skills in diverse athletic competitions. Note: This festival may also, though very rarely, take place at a kindergarten or preschool.</description>
<picurl>161025.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2670" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-07">
<name>school festival - TO BE SPLIT AND DELETED</name>
<description>THIS TAG NEEDS TO BE SPLIT: into http://anidb.net/perl-bin/animedb.pl?show=tag&tagid=6119&reltb=eptb [school culture festival] and http://anidb.net/perl-bin/animedb.pl?show=tag&tagid=2665&reltb=eptb [school sports festival] The obligatory school festival (or cultural fair) with cosplay cafe, haunted house, theatre performance, and food booths cannot be missing in any school setting. For good measure there may also be an athletics or sports festival in this anime.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2672" parentid="2834" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-03-05">
<name>Japan</name>
<description>Japan is a sovereign island nation in East Asia. Located in the Pacific Ocean, it lies off the eastern coast of the Asian mainland and stretches from the Sea of Okhotsk in the north to the East China Sea and China in the southwest. Source: Wikipedia</description>
<picurl>65689.png</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2741" parentid="2891" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-12-14">
<name>large breasts</name>
<description>Large breasts are breasts a fair notch larger than average, as found in some adolescent girls or fully grown women; however, as anime has no upper limit to breast size, the definition applies somewhat differently. To be considered large, breasts in anime must be bigger than real-life natural ones or natural-seeming fake ones, to the point they`d appear weirdly or even abnormally large in real-life females. On the high end of the spectrum, breasts that are as big as the character`s head or possibly a bit bigger are still considered large; however, breasts that take at least as much space as the rest of the chest or the abdomen, or that are almost as big but have an absurdly unnatural shape, are the less common http://anidb.net/t1774 [gigantic breasts] instead.</description>
<picurl>161014.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2749" parentid="2604" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-11-08">
<name>nudity</name>
<description>Nudity is the state of wearing no clothing. The wearing of clothing is exclusively a human characteristic. The amount of clothing worn depends on functional considerations (such as a need for warmth or protection from the elements) and social considerations. In some situations the minimum amount of clothing (i.e. covering of a person`s genitals) may be socially acceptable, while in others much more clothing is expected. Note: Refer to further guidance on http://wiki.anidb.net/w/Categories:Content_Indicators [the Wiki page] for how to apply tag weights for content indicators. People, as individuals and in groups, have varying attitudes towards their own nudity. Some people are relaxed about appearing less than fully clothed in front of others, while others are uncomfortable or inhibited in that regard. People are nude in a variety of situations, and whether they are prepared to disrobe in front of others depends on the social context in which the issue arises. For example, people need to bathe without clothing, some people also sleep in the nude, some prefer to sunbathe in the nude or at least topless, while others are nude in other situations. Some people adopt naturism as a lifestyle. Though the wearing of clothes is the social norm in most cultures, some cultures, groups and individuals are more relaxed about nudity, though attitudes often depend on context. On the other hand, some people feel uncomfortable in the presence of any nudity, and the presence of a nude person in a public place can give rise to controversy, irrespective of the attitude of the person who is nude. Besides meeting social disapproval, in some places public nudity may constitute a crime of indecent exposure. Many people have strong views on nudity, which to them can involve issues and standards of modesty, decency and morality. Some people have an psychological aversion to nudity, called gymnophobia. Many people regard nudity to be inherently sexual and erotic. Nudity is to be found in a multitude of media, including art, photography, film and on the Internet. It is a factor in adult entertainment of various types. Especially gratuitous fanservice anime shows tend to show their (usually female) characters frequently without any clothes, though often hiding genitals through the means of additions like steam. Source: wiki</description>
<picurl>60576.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2770" parentid="2653" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-25">
<name>violent retribution for accidental infringement</name>
<description>A comedy / slapstick element often found in Ecchi anime: The hilarity derives from spontaneous embarrassment, overreaction of the "victim" (girl), immediate retribution for a seemingly inappropriate act, and a sense of pity with the supposed "aggressor" (boy). Typically a boy will - through no fault of his own - stumble into a girl, thus invading her personal space. In the process the boy may e.g. pull down her skirt, grab the girl`s breasts, or accidentally kiss her. Any level-headed girl would see the accident just for what it is. Not so the girl with an overly developed sense of modesty, and a thing for violence. She - often a tsundere - will clobber the boy with excessive brutality.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2775" parentid="2202" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2013-03-15">
<name>humanoid alien</name>
<description>Humanoids are aliens, intelligent beings who do not originate from Earth, but have a striking similarity to humans or at least show the basic body layout, i.e. two arms and legs, head with two eyes and ears, one nose and mouth. Though the latter - head-related features - may vary. As "DearS" shows some aliens actually exhibit super-human beauty, or as in the case of "Onegai Teacher" they are genetically compatible to humans for some strange reason.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2778" parentid="2858" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-11-09">
<name>slow when it comes to love</name>
<description>The main protagonists in this anime have a very hard time trying to express their feelings to each other. They simply will not finally confess their love. In some cases this romance element is based on unrequited love, or an absurd amount of shyness.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2782" parentid="2858" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-09-03">
<name>shoujo ai</name>
<description>Shoujo Ai means girls love, and thus explores what happens when two girls (or women) fall in love. This is not to be mistaken for http://anidb.net/t2695 [Yuri] which is (or, at least, how this term is often used by the western audience) used in adult works. This is not; that means there is no graphic sex. The male version is http://anidb.net/t2783 [Shounen Ai]. http://anidb.net/t7146 [Cute girls doing cute things (CGDCT)] is often mistaken as low level Yuri or Shoujo Ai. If there is no Yuri or Shoujo Ai subtext, i.e. if there is no romantic subtext, only tag CGDCT. Please note: CGDCT and yuri/shoujo ai are not mutually exclusive; it is possible to have an anime tagged both.</description>
<picurl>210060.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2783" parentid="2858" weight="100" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-08-04">
<name>shounen ai</name>
<description>Shounen Ai means boys love, and thus explores what happens when two boys (or men) fall in love. This is not to be mistaken for http://anidb.net/t2723 [Yaoi] which is (or, at least, how this term is often used by the western audience) used in adult works. This is not; that means there is no graphical sex. The female version is http://anidb.net/t2782 [Shoujo Ai].</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2784" parentid="2858" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-12-01">
<name>sudden girlfriend appearance</name>
<description>Sudden Girlfriend Appearance anime involve a sudden change in the main character`s life where (s)he suddenly gets confronted with an individual (s)he`s sexually attracted to, the two of them inevitably becoming a couple.</description>
<picurl>210066.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2786" parentid="2858" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-01-21">
<name>love polygon</name>
<description>A love polygon refers to a romantic relationship involving n people. Although a love triangle is not limited to just heterosexual relationships, in anime, it usually deals with two females liking one male and vice versa.</description>
<picurl>10989.gif</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2788" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-12-21">
<name>confession</name>
<description>Someone confesses his/her love to someone else.</description>
<picurl>160903.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2791" parentid="6230" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-12-25">
<name>stereotypes</name>
<description>This show presents stereotypes, which are generalizations about a group of people. Examples would be saying that people from a certain country or with a certain hair color are stupid. If the show deals with comedy, the stereotypes are likely to be played on for laughs; if the show is a parody, the stereotypes will be exaggerated to have their flaws exposed and may be used as a form of social commentary.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2798" parentid="2609" infobox="true" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2019-02-14">
<name>manga</name>
<description>Manga is the lifeblood that drives the anime industry. Everything and its mother is based on manga. However! There are exceptions where the manga was not the basis for the anime. It`s common practice to make manga adaptations of many popular anime, there`s a manga based on Evangelion, and two (one shounen and one shoujo) based on each of Escaflowne and Mahou Tsukai Tai. Also it`s quite common to release manga and anime versions of a story in parallel, for instance Nadesico and Shoujo Kakumei Utena. There are also cases where an anime continues in a manga, as in the case of Angel Beats! and Angel Beats: Heaven`s Door, or reverse. See also http://anidb.net/t6493 [manhua] and http://anidb.net/t5010 [manhwa].</description>
<picurl>215593.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2817" parentid="2856" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-08">
<name>skimpy clothing</name>
<description>When a job needs to get done you need the appropriate clothing on the appropriate persons. That calls for preferably scantily clad young ladies. Spies will dress in sexy outfits, even when the mission explicitly calls for them to not to be noticed. Female warriors will charge into battle wearing armour that does not protect the vital organs. Bridge officers on a military starship will be issued go-go boots with their uniforms. Examples are the women in VanDread, AIKa or the most famous incarnation of that tag, the Strike Witches and their precursor the Sky Girls.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2821" parentid="2856" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-06">
<name>sudden naked girl appearance</name>
<description>A character or group of characters are simply minding their own business, when suddenly, a naked girl appears. It does not matter how or why, but a naked someone is there. Sometimes the naked girl is not happy about this. Usually this is a fanservice element, but not always.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2823" parentid="2856" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-06">
<name>paper clothes</name>
<description>Worn clothing appears paper-thin and takes little abuse to be shredded or torn from the body. This is common in ecchi anime where the main storyline involves some type of fighting but consists primarily of dialogue and fanservice (Ikkitousen and Platonic Heart). Various girls’ clothing exploding as if made of rice paper is a very enticing prospect.</description>
<picurl>150776.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2824" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>pseudo tentacle rape scene</name>
<description>If this was porn she (or rather the audience) would have even more fun!</description>
<picurl>160554.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2826" parentid="2856" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-01-27">
<name>pantsu</name>
<description>"Panties" in Japanese. Upskirt views in various positions are typical, however all forms of partial or fully exposed panties are accepted. Exposure is usually accidental, but may also be deliberate. Pantsu views may be exclusive to the viewer without impacting any characters. Bikinis are not pantsu.</description>
<picurl>5721.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2834" parentid="2630" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-10-04">
<name>Asia</name>
<description>Asia is Earth`s largest and most populous continent, located primarily in the eastern and northern hemispheres and sharing the continental landmass of Eurasia with the continent of Europe. Asia covers an area of 44,579,000 square kilometers, about 30% of Earth`s total land area and 8.7% of the Earth`s total surface area. The continent, which has long been home to the majority of the human population, was the site of many of the first civilizations. Asia is notable for not only its overall large size and population, but also dense and large settlements as well as vast barely populated regions within the continent of 4.4 billion people. Source: Wikipedia</description>
<picurl>192245.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2841" parentid="2611" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-12-26">
<name>action</name>
<description>Action anime usually involve a fairly straightforward story of good guys versus bad guys, where most disputes are resolved by using physical force. It often contains a lot of shooting, explosions and fighting.</description>
<picurl>211261.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2846" parentid="7050" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-10-04">
<name>science fiction</name>
<description>Science fiction stories usually focus on how situations could be different in the future when we are more technologically advanced; due to either our own achievements or having met with other civilizations whom we have learned from.</description>
<picurl>212180.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2849" parentid="7050" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2005-05-07">
<name>fantasy</name>
<description>Fantasy is a genre of fiction that uses magic and other supernatural phenomena as a primary element of plot, theme, or setting. Many works within the genre take place in fictional worlds where magic is common. Fantasy is generally distinguished from science fiction and horror by the expectation that it steers clear of (pseudo-)scientific and macabre themes, respectively, though there is a great deal of overlap between the three (which are subgenres of speculative fiction). In popular culture, the genre of fantasy is dominated by its medievalist form, especially since the worldwide success of The Lord of the Rings books by J. R. R. Tolkien. In its broadest sense however, fantasy comprises works by many writers, artists, filmmakers, and musicians, from ancient myths and legends to many recent works embraced by a wide audience today. Fantasy is a vibrant area of academic study in a number of disciplines (English, cultural studies, comparative literature, history, medieval studies). Work in this area ranges widely, from the structuralist theory of Tzvetan Todorov, which emphasizes the fantastic as a liminal space, to work on the connections (political, historical, literary) between medievalism and popular culture Source: Wiki</description>
<picurl>68768.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2853" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="500" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-02-13">
<name>comedy</name>
<description>Anime whose central struggle causes hilarious results. These stories are built upon funny characters, situations and events. A comedy anime is laced with humour and sets out to provoke laughter from the audience. Japanese humour can be a bit strange to westerners, so if you`re new to this type of humour, just bear with it; it`ll most likely grow on you if you`re a fan of other kinds of comedy.</description>
<picurl>198104.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2854" parentid="2611" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-08">
<name>henshin</name>
<description>Japanese for "transformation" (metamorphosis or disguise). A "henshin anime" is any anime, where the characters or their costumes transform, such as Sailor Moon. The henshin switches on the character`s special powers, and is frequently accompanied by a costume change. Often the change of clothing is the only outward indicator that the character has changed and yet nobody seems to notice the hero`s true self. Most henshin heroes have a special item which they use to change into their heroic form. These items are usually activated by a command phrase (which is often in Engrish, for some reason), triggering a transformation sequence.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2856" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="600" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-05">
<name>ecchi</name>
<description>Fan service is found in many anime, in many forms. When the service has a distinctly sexual slant to it, and it appears to be a major focus of the show, then it`s safe to assume you`re watching ecchi. The word "ecchi" is used by English-speaking anime fans to refer to refer to soft-core pornographic or sexually suggestive anime and manga. This is a western invention; in Japanese, it is a catch-all term for all things anyhow sexual in nature, not being limited to porn, but also not really considered a "milder" term, as it may also refer to sexual intercourse itself. The term "ecchi" in Japanese comes from the pronunciation of the letter "H" in English, which is rendered into Japanese syllabary as エッチ, which in turn is transliterated in the English alphabet as "ecchi" or "etchi". It is not, as many believe, short for "hentai" -- that, too, seems to be a western invention. It is, however, nearly as misunderstood and misapplied a term as "hentai". The line between ecchi and hentai, from the western perspective over these terms, can be hard to draw at times; one good rule of thumb is: if it was aired on Japanese public TV at all, it probably wasn`t hentai. Ecchi usually features all the specifics to human anatomy that can only be found in anime, and generally avoids full nudity, instead abusing of panty shots. Hentai, on the other hand, will usually show full frontal nudity in some explicit form, including genitalia, and full, intimate sex scenes. At its mildest, ecchi is composed of double entendres, big misunderstandings, and sexual farce; at its most explicit, it is still in the realm of softcore pornography, with full breast shots, full back nudity and similar content, but no display of genitalia. Another good way to distinguish the two is looking for animated sex scenes; if one is found, you have generally left the genre entirely, though a few borderline exceptions apply here. For AniDB`s purposes, the distinction between explicit ecchi and actual hentai is simple: if it was sold with a 18+ restriction in its country of origin, it is hentai; if it was sold without it, it is ecchi. Source: TV Tropes</description>
<picurl>32416.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2858" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-12-01">
<name>romance</name>
<description>Romance describes a story that deals with love between two or more characters typically also having an optimistic ending. Romance is also a difficulty encountered when creating a harem.</description>
<picurl>210061.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2859" parentid="2611" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-09-04">
<name>harem</name>
<description>Harem is an entertainment-related trope which is characterized by three or more characters, normally female, who for some reason are in the presence and under the influence of one character, generally male, according to a few genre-defining guidelines; here it will be assumed, for simplicity of language, that the harem lead is a male character and the members are female characters. Though that is the rule, there are exceptions; a story in which there is one female character and several male characters is normally called a "http://anidb.net/t2792 [reverse harem]", or sometimes also "male harem". Aside from the swapping of the characters` genders, the trope`s details are mostly the same, with the majority of the changes relating to the differences in behavior between men and women of the characters` age range. It is also possible to create harems with homosexual relationships, again with very few changes to the main antics themselves. The harem may not have more than only one lead, as that would be a love polygon, or less than three members, as one would form a couple and two would make a love triangle. As a defining rule of harem, the interactions between the lead and each of the individual members are filled with romantically or sexually loaded content, either implicitly, through innuendo or subtext, or explicitly, through text or actions, and those actions are a key plot element. Generally, the female characters` looks and personalities will vary a lot among the ones present in one single series, but quite rarely will they actually differ from the common stock archetypes, which are known, well-defined, and easy to copy; for this reason, the genre as a whole is often considered repetitive. Usually, the characters involved directly in this trope are in the late teenager to young adult age range, but that is not mandatory. Sexually charged behavior on the lead`s part pretty much can`t be avoided, and it`s typical to see him stamped as a pervert by some or all of the members, regardless of whether he is one; the sexual tones also applies to the depiction of the harem members, often leading the genre to labeled sexist. The lead will often suffer very violent retribution for his behavior, which has attracted criticism of gratuitous violence as well. Most of the harem members will be romantically or sometimes sexually interested in the one male character, and in him alone; that, however, is not an absolute rule, and indeed sometimes none of the female characters are really interested at first, so the protagonist has to build relationships with them from scratch. That idea comes in large part from visual novels; it is quite common for visual novels to revolve around controlling the male lead and have him build relationships with either as many female characters as possible or with one of them, the latter being more common for visual novels with branched story paths; a large portion of those visual novels also feature erotic content, which may be hard to adapt to TV series. It may be also possible that the harem is only a support to the existing or predictable relationship between the lead and the most important member; additionally, the lead may end up in relationships with most or all of the harem members, with the agreement of all, in a setting normally called "harem ending".</description>
<picurl>94602.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2864" parentid="2607" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-12-01">
<name>daily life</name>
<description>The antics of the protagonists do not take place in some exotic setting or time, but in everyday life. When not "at the job" this means getting up in the morning, making meals, house cleaning, going shopping or out to eat, visiting the bath house or spa, leisure activities in the spare time, etc. The time "on the job" for students is School Life, for others working in their profession. Daily Life is basically a synonym for everything normal, repetitive, and trivial happening to your average person.</description>
<picurl>210069.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2869" parentid="2607" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2017-12-01">
<name>school life</name>
<description>Since a large part of the anime audience still takes part in school life or is visiting college, it is only natural to choose a setting the audience can identify with, be it elementary, middle, or high school. For the older viewers a college setting with more mature real-life problems is appropriate. And since clubs take up so much time in the lives of students, these are obviously also important.</description>
<picurl>210062.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2874" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-05-07">
<name>disaster</name>
<description>A disaster is a large-scale situation that causes great loss of or damage or threat to life, health, property, society, or the environment, irrespective of its source or cause. Disasters have substantial, long-lasting negative repercussions, and great effort must be spent in order to undo or mitigate their effects.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2881" parentid="2607" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-01-21">
<name>sports</name>
<description>Sports anime revolves around a recreational physical activity or skill. In addition they often adhere to certain genre conventions, the emphasis on training and practice in preparation for competition, characters desire for self improvement, and pursuit of a specific goal.</description>
<picurl>212185.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2888" parentid="2607" infobox="true" weight="400" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-16">
<name>coming of age</name>
<description>In the strict sense the Coming of age describes a young person`s transition from adolescence to adulthood. In anime the term is used in a more general sense where the protagonists have to face a challenge, make an important decision in their life, take on responsibility, or learn a lesson, and by overcoming these obstacles they reach a higher level of maturity.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2891" parentid="2608" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-12-31">
<name>breasts</name>
<description>The female bust size matters! Or does it? The three subcategories spell out the sizes that relate to fetishes, be they gigantic, large or small. Normal sized breasts are not a fetish, it seems. The tag is not only used for ecchi anime, but also for hentai shows as well.</description>
<picurl>161015.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2910" parentid="6249" weight="300" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2012-10-08">
<name>parental abandonment</name>
<description>In Japan it is a common custom for parents to leave their children alone at home and embark on a lifelong trip around the world once they hit the tender age of 14, sometimes even earlier. Of course this is done because the parents believe their children are independent enough to get their act together. But little do they know about the small secrets their offspring has, such as a childhood fiancé(e) or even a forbidden incestuous love between their (often not-blood-related) children. Of course aside from having a huge house, financial support is provided as well. Usually through the means of MAGICAL MONEY. In rare cases the parents actually die (shortly) before embarking on their world-trip, which is self-evidently used as an important plot device in the development of the child.</description>
<picurl>38239.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2016-12-04">
<name>unsorted</name>
<description>a bunch of tags that still need to be either deleted or moved into proper places.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3108" parentid="2653" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2011-07-20">
<name>catastrophic gadgets</name>
<description>Comedy element: One of the characters in the anime tends to "invent", "create", or "call into existence" all sorts of wacky gadgets. The intent is to help the other protagonists in some way. Only that this fails every single time, ending in a catastrophe.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3444" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-15">
<name>hot springs visit</name>
<description>An onsen is a term for hot springs in the Japanese language, though the term is often used to describe the bathing facilities and inns around the hot springs. Often the cast of a show somehow ends up going to an onsen because of various reasons, such as winning a lottery ticket. Usually used for fanservice purpose as it gives the staff the opportunity to draw the characters nude and raise the DVD sales. Another cheap variant is the http://anidb.net/t4290 [sentou episode]. See also http://anidb.net/t2830 [furo scene], http://anidb.net/t5846 [beach episode], and http://anidb.net/t6046 [pool episode].</description>
<picurl>160784.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="3679" parentid="2858" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-26">
<name>engaged to an alien</name>
<description>The human protagonist in this show is engaged to an alien for some strange reason. Comedy element used to create many strange situations and misunderstandings.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3721" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2012-10-07">
<name>RPG elements</name>
<description>The anime shows elements of a `R`ole `P`laying `G`ame, either as part of a parody or because the anime is actually based on an RPG. Typical elements: When collecting items, beating opponents, or levelling up a distinct (often childishly sounding) sound cue is played. A HUD (`H`eads `U`p `D`isplay) may also be presenting in combat, showing vital player and "enemy" statistics.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="3738" parentid="2202" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-02-05">
<name>aliens living on earth</name>
<description>There`s an alien or a hive of aliens blending into society near you!</description>
<picurl>70750.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="3842" parentid="6151" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2010-10-31">
<name>TV censoring</name>
<description>The TV version is censored and later DVD/BD releases are uncensored, so the money-grubbing capitalists can make a couple more bucks at our expense.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4323" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2009-02-04">
<name>spacing out</name>
<description>A comedy element: The character starts to daydream or fantasize about some topic. The typical complete lack of reality makes the spacing out funny. Especially when the protagonist mumbles to himself / herself and friends hear this. Promptly teasing the possibly lovestruck and very embarrassed protagonist.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4333" parentid="6230" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-07-06">
<name>predominantly female cast</name>
<description>A show with a predominantly female cast has mostly females as main and secondary cast members while few if any male characters have major roles. This also applies when a male lead is surrounded by females of lesser individual plot relevance, such as in a harem setting.</description>
<picurl>70752.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="5455" parentid="6149" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-22">
<name>creepy laugh</name>
<description>At least one character in the show inexplicably and repetitively seems to have the urgent need to laugh in a creepy, loud and usually very annoying way. For male bad guys this seems to be a must, but some of the uppity (rich) female characters use the laugh as part of their condescending attitude as well.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5834" parentid="6233" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2009-05-25">
<name>show within a show</name>
<description>A fictional TV (or radio, or stage) show that takes place within an actual TV show; or, occasionally, a fictional instalment or incarnation of an actual show. Many comedies have short one-off gags where they parody existing shows. Example: A large part of Martian Successor Nadesico is centred around the fictional popular anime Gekigangar III, which is being watched by several characters of the Nadesico crew.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5835" parentid="2856" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2019-07-28">
<name>Gainax bounce</name>
<description>A term that has come to describe often exaggerated, very jiggly, fluid, and painstakingly detailed animation of female characters` bouncing breasts. The term has its roots in http://anidb.net/a185 [Top o Nerae!] — Gunbuster, Gainax`s first OVA (1988), in which the Gainax bounce is found unabated in the three female characters of Noriko, Kazumi, and Jung.</description>
<picurl>166074.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="5863" parentid="2798" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2018-10-06">
<name>Weekly Shounen Jump</name>
<description>The Weekly Shounen Jump is a Japanese manga magazine released on a weekly basis. Its main target audience consists of young males and it features several manga titles. The magazine was created by http://anidb.net/cr780 [Shueisha] in July, 1968, and was originally only called Shounen Jump, because it was not published every week at the time. A number of very famous shounen manga were or are published in it, such as http://anidb.net/a386 [Hokuto no Ken], http://anidb.net/a231 [Dragon Ball], http://anidb.net/a942 [City Hunter], http://anidb.net/a826 [Saint Seiya], http://anidb.net/a590 [Slam Dunk], http://anidb.net/a312 [Yuu Yuu Hakushou], http://anidb.net/a69 [One Piece], http://anidb.net/a239 [Naruto], http://anidb.net/a2369 [Bleach], http://anidb.net/a4563 [Death Note], http://anidb.net/a3468 [Gintama], to name a few of the most well-known.</description>
<picurl>66685.png</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="5943" parentid="2931" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="false" update="2008-06-14">
<name>misunderstanding</name>
<description>Suggests that a large portion of storyline revolves around a rather large misunderstanding between two or more characters, usually forming long lasting situations of separation or hostility between all those involved. A large portion of the story may be dedicated to gradually working all parties into a mutual understanding to true intentions or changes of heart.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5952" parentid="2874" weight="200" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-08-25">
<name>end of the world</name>
<description>The imminent end of the world may range from the total destruction of the planet Earth, to the destruction of Earth`s surface, or to the point where human life on the planet is no longer possible, aka the end of humanity. In any case it looks grim, and the protagonists battle to preserve what they can.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6021" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-07">
<name>gender bender</name>
<description>Term used to refer to a person who takes on the role of their opposite gender. This often only reaches to the extent of cross-dressing (involving physical appearance and clothing only), but in rarer cases, involves a total gender swap (which seems to be more common in anime) - where the willing or unwilling victim receives a body opposite of their original gender (either permanently or temporarily), with all natural parts per their new body fully (or just all-out amply) included. Example of cross-dressing gender bender: "Maria+Holic" Examples of body-swap gender bender: "Kashimashi: Girl meets Girl", "Birdy the Mighty Decode"</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6046" parentid="6148" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-15">
<name>pool episode</name>
<description>An episode playing at the pool, mostly in school, sometimes outside of it when the cast does not have a chance for a beach episode. Usually used for fanservice purpose as it gives the staff the opportunity to draw the characters in swimsuits and raise the DVD sales. The cheap version of the http://anidb.net/t5846 [beach episode]. Other variants are the http://anidb.net/t3444 [onsen episode] and the http://anidb.net/t2830 [furo scene], used when it is too cold for a beach/pool episode. See also http://anidb.net/t2830 [furo scene].</description>
<picurl>160904.jpg</picurl>
</tag>
<tag id="6148" parentid="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>TO BE MOVED TO EPISODE</name>
<description>Tags under this parent tag are going to be moved to episode tags and removed from the anime they`re currently assigned to. They will be blocked from the anime system once that move is complete. Please help with that job if you know what episodes they should be assigned to.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6149" parentid="30" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>TO BE MOVED TO CHARACTER</name>
<description>Tags under this parent tag are going to be moved to character tags and removed from the anime they`re currently assigned to. They will be blocked from the anime system once that move is complete. Please help with that job if you know what characters they should be assigned to.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6151" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-09-10">
<name>technical aspects</name>
<description>It may sometimes be useful to know about technical aspects of a show, such as information about its broadcasting or censorship. Such information can be found here.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6230" parentid="2605" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-20">
<name>cast</name>
</tag>
<tag id="6233" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2015-08-11">
<name>tropes</name>
<description>A trope is a commonly recurring literary and rhetorical devices, motifs or clichés in creative works. This use is a broader redefining of a literary trope, the use of figurative language, via word, phrase, or even an image, for artistic effect, such as using a figure of speech. Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
<tag id="6249" parentid="2607" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2014-10-31">
<name>family life</name>
</tag>
<tag id="7050" parentid="2611" weight="0" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" verified="true" update="2019-04-18">
<name>speculative fiction</name>
<description>Speculative fiction is an umbrella genre encompassing fiction with certain elements that do not exist in the real world, often in the context of supernatural, futuristic or other imaginative themes. This includes, but is not limited to, science fiction, fantasy, superhero fiction, horror, utopian and dystopian fiction, fairytale fantasy, supernatural fiction, as well as combinations thereof. Source: Wikipedia</description>
</tag>
</tags>
<characters>
<character id="2354" type="main character in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="351">2.61</rating>
<name>Yuuki Rito</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The male protagonist of To Love-Ru, Rito is a 16 year-old high-school student. Rito used to be on the soccer team in junior high and was quite good, but quit because he was constantly helping his father with his mangaka duties, thus did not want to leave his sister Mikan alone in the house. Mikan comments he is very good at the most "useless little things", like crane and festival games. Along with the numerous useless little things Rito is good at, he is also an accomplished florist/gardener/horticulturalist.</description>
<picture>61497.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="192" picture="41287.jpg">Watanabe Akeno</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2355" type="main character in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="650">8.07</rating>
<name>Lala Satalin Deviluke</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The female protagonist of To Love-Ru, Lala is the princess of Deviluke. A rather childish girl, she is somewhat naïve of the culture and familiarities on Earth. Lala initially runs away from home, citing she does not wish to get married to any of her arranged suitors. She enjoys making all manners of inventions (usually designed as pranks) and uses them frequently, often prompting some disastrous effect or another. Upon arriving on Earth, Lala pretends to love Rito to keep herself from getting married, but does exactly what she did not intend, after she misinterprets what Rito shouts in self-defence. Throughout the series, she always tries to get Rito to love her more, and barely shows any form of negativity towards him; she even states it is impossible for her to hate him.</description>
<picture>61495.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5" picture="233827.jpg">Tomatsu Haruka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2356" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-02-08">
<rating votes="85">5.82</rating>
<name>Peke</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Lala`s all costume robot, who acts as a module to form her clothing. Peke is exceptionally devoted to Lala and has the ability to shapeshift into any kind of clothing for her to wear, but this also drains her power supply. As her batteries run out, the clothing Lala wears will slowly dissolve, until it completely disappears. To recharge, Peke simply needs to sleep.</description>
<picture>17592.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="600" picture="148972.jpg">Arai Satomi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2357" type="secondary cast in" update="2018-09-16">
<rating votes="533">8.48</rating>
<name>Konjiki no Yami</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A dispassionate, withdrawn assassin, Golden Darkness is hired by one of Lala`s arranged suitors, Lacospo to kill Rito, until she breaks the contract, noting the true nature behind her target. Golden Darkness is currently staying on Earth, roaming around the city streets and Sainan High, with a motivation to continue her duty to assassinate Rito, although she has yet to accomplish this (hinting she only said this as an excuse to stay on Earth). Commonly referred as "Yami-chan", she spends her time reading books and magazines, while eating taiyaki (it is the only thing she eats on Earth since it is the first food offered by Rito, prior to spending a night at the Yuuki residence for a sukiyaki dinner). By her planet`s calculations, she is 24 years-old, despite having an appearance of an 11 year-old and has a weakness towards anything slimy. http://anidb.net/ch2387 [Eve] from http://anidb.net/a3321 [Black Cat], another of http://anidb.net/cr2985 [Yabuki Kentaro]`s works, and her are alternative reality versions of each other.</description>
<picture>61500.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="304" picture="17139.jpg">Fukuen Misato</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2358" type="main character in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="267">6.07</rating>
<name>Sairenji Haruna</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>One of Rito`s classmates and the girl of his affections, Haruna has similar feelings for him, having been attracted to his kind, gentle nature since junior high. Despite her growing love for Rito, which she believes to be unrequited, she usually suppresses her feelings and cannot confess to him because of her friendship with Lala, who also loves Rito. However, with some encouragement, she tells Lala of her ordeal, to which Lala accepts, claiming Haruna as her rival for Rito`s heart, while remaining friends. She lives with her older sister in an apartment and has a severe fear of ghosts and the supernatural, the exception being Shizu Murasame, to an extent. When frightened, she has a habit of grabbing the nearest thing around her -- typically Rito -- and swinging wildly, in an attempt to get rid of whatever frightens her. Some people know about her love for Rito like Oshizu, Ryouko, Nana, and Lala.</description>
<picture>61496.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="89" picture="148709.jpg">Yahagi Sayuri</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2359" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="54">2.93</rating>
<name>Saruyama Ken`ichi</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The perverted best friend of Rito, Kenichi has known him since junior high and is more open and obvious of his obsession with girls and is one of the few male characters Rito can talk to about his situations involving Haruna or Lala.</description>
<picture>17595.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="65" picture="170428.jpg">Yoshino Hiroyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2360" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="210">5.57</rating>
<name>Momioka Risa</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Momioka Risa is one of the mischievous, cheerful best friends of Haruna, Risa and Mio spend as much time as they can with her and Lala. Whenever Lala inquires about Earth culture and habits, the two divulge as much information as they can for her (although it is often misleading and perverted). Risa and Mio are known for their playful habit of groping other girls.</description>
<picture>126812.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="253" picture="222833.jpg">Yuzuki Ryouka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2361" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-04-01">
<rating votes="116">5.36</rating>
<name>Sawada Mio</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>One of the mischievous, cheerful best friends of Haruna, Risa and Mio spend as much time as they can with her and Lala. Whenever Lala inquires about Earth culture and habits, the two divulge as much information as they can for her (although it is often misleading and perverted). Risa and Mio are known for their playful habit of groping other girls.</description>
<picture>184983.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="540" picture="41046.jpg">Chiba Chiemi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2362" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-04-01">
<rating votes="149">6.87</rating>
<name>Run Elsie Jewelria</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>As Run is from planet Memorze, she can change gender in mind and body upon triggering a specific stimulus; in her case, a sneeze. As a girl, Run is in love with Rito, due to the kiss, and blames Lala for her misfortunes. However, her boy form, Ren, is still in competition, albeit one-sided, with Rito for Lala`s hand in marriage. Currently, Run is a famous idol, having released several albums.</description>
<picture>184984.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="142" picture="68482.jpg">Ooura Fuyuka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2363" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="62">5.03</rating>
<name>Ren Elsie Jewelria</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A childhood friend of Lala, Ren is infamously known for wearing girls clothing during his play dates with Lala when he was a child. He arrives on Earth to win Lala by proving he is "man enough" for her, but becomes jealous of her relationship with Rito. Due to his pursuit of her, he accidentally gives Rito his first kiss. While Ren is furious, it has an unexpected consequence towards his "alter ego". As Ren is from planet Memorze, he can change gender in mind and body upon triggering a specific stimulus; in his case, a sneeze. As a girl, Run is in love with Rito, due to the kiss, and blames Lala for her misfortunes, while Ren is still in competition, albeit one-sided, with Rito for Lala`s hand in marriage.</description>
<picture>17600.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="142" picture="68482.jpg">Ooura Fuyuka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2364" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="441">8.44</rating>
<name>Kotegawa Yui</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>An uptight, high-strung girl placed in Rito`s class during the second year, Yui has little to no tolerance for anything she does not consider to be "acceptable behavior". Her haughty opinions, quick temper, and habit of speaking her mind often results in her vocally reprimanding classmates. Yui quickly grows annoyed and disgusted by the eccentricities and bizarre actions, particularly with regards to Rito and Lala. Unfortunately, almost every encounter with Rito usually ends up with her embarrassed, and though her complicated nature prevents her from easing her behaviour, she does slowly warm up to his usual antics and develops feelings for Rito.</description>
<picture>61498.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="308" picture="44975.jpg">Nazuka Kaori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2365" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="173">6.54</rating>
<name>Murasame Shizu</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The ghost of a girl who died in the old abandoned school building 400 years ago, Oshizu is sincere, kind, and very curious about the modern world, but has a severe fear of dogs, likened to Haruna`s level of fear to the supernatural. When frightened, she can emit blasts of mental stress, blowing apart various objects and surroundings, but is also capable of manipulating others through sheer willpower. Since her meeting with Rito and the others, she begins exploring the world outside the old school building. Oshizu is aware of Haruna`s crush on Rito by her ability to sense feelings while possessing another person and becomes very supportive towards cheering Haruna into confessing her feelings to him.</description>
<picture>61499.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="10" picture="226529.jpg">Noto Mamiko</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2366" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-04-01">
<rating votes="157">6.01</rating>
<name>Tenjouin Saki</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The arrogant queen bee of the school, third-year student Saki consistently tries to one-up Lala, stating there can only be "queen" in Sainan High. She once tries to seduce Rito to make Lala jealous, but when that does not work, Saki takes up any excuse to physically assault Rito. She gains a crush on Zastin, only to be horrified when she discovers he is Lala`s servant. However, this makes her very determined to win his heart, at any cost.</description>
<picture>184979.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="12" picture="184301.jpg">Kawasumi Ayako</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2367" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-04-01">
<rating votes="137">6.63</rating>
<name>Kujou Rin</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Saki`s loyal and assisting friends, Rin is skilled in the kendo arts and has been a loyal bodyguard of Saki for years, as her family has always served the Tenjouin in this position.</description>
<picture>184981.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="602" picture="79633.jpg">Hashimoto Mai</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2368" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-04-01">
<rating votes="85">3.62</rating>
<name>Fujisaki Aya</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Saki`s loyal and assisting friends, The bespectacled Aya is weak-willed and became associated with Saki after she and Rin protected her from bullies when they were children.</description>
<picture>184982.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="591" picture="226209.jpg">Mizuhashi Kaori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2369" type="secondary cast in" update="2016-04-01">
<rating votes="142">7.26</rating>
<name>Mikado Ryouko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The provocative school doctor at Sainan High, Ryouko helps out other extraterrestrials on Earth in various manners, usually those dealing with medical care, though she does offer students a variety of her own concoctions. Formerly an operative for a shadowy, black market extraterrestrial organization, she fled from her superiors to Earth in hopes of hiding her identity. Proof of her non-human origins are the elf-like ears hidden by her short hair, though it has yet been specified what her species is.</description>
<picture>184980.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="603" picture="223012.jpg">Jou Masako</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2370" type="secondary cast in" update="2009-01-14">
<rating votes="80">3.56</rating>
<name>Kouchou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The unnamed principal of Sainan High is well-known throughout campus as a pervert. He will impulsively enrol girls into the school body, so as to ogle and grope them without hesitation, though this is not restricted in Sainan High, but in public, as well.</description>
<picture>17607.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="604" picture="154161.jpg">Ogata Ken`ichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2371" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="428">8.44</rating>
<name>Yuuki Mikan</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Yuuki Mikan is Rito`s independent and reliable 11 year-old sister, Mikan takes care of the housework while their parents are away on business. In contrast to her brother, she is very mature and does not hesitate to tease him, going as far as stating they aren`t blood related, just for a laugh. Mikan also seems to have a certain lack of respect for Rito because of this (she hardly ever addresses him by his honorific as an older brother), but does answer him "Onii-chan" as thanks for trying so hard to take care of her when she develops a fever and when he got her a Christmas present. Mikan may not show it, but she cares very deeply for Rito and misses his company, and states how they used to play together before Lala entered their lives.</description>
<picture>126813.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="176" picture="192484.jpg">Hanazawa Kana</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2372" type="secondary cast in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="45">6.85</rating>
<name>Zastin</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Lala`s personal bodyguard and the best swordsman on Deviluke. Initially, Zastin disapproves of Rito, deeming him weak and subsequently soughts to test his strength. However, once Rito exclaims his opinion of marriage in self-defense, Zastin is swayed by his words (though not in the way Rito intends) and summarily approves of him, believing he truly understands Lala`s feelings.</description>
<picture>17609.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="139" picture="29283.jpg">Koyasu Takehito</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="2373" type="secondary cast in" update="2017-09-12">
<rating votes="18">3.74</rating>
<name>Gido Lucion Deviluke</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The King of Deviluke and Emperor of the known universe, Gido is the father of Lala, Nana, and Momo. Despite his near omnipotent power, he has the physical appearance of a child, looking slightly devilish, with shark-like teeth, spiky black hair, and the characteristic Devilukean tail; while his daughters` tails end in spades, his appears as a wicked looking trident. Gido`s personality borders juvenile delinquency and perversion, thus Lala claims the only reason he wants her to get married is so he can step down as king and be free to pursue his perverted hobbies. Lala states his current appearance is due to him using too much power during the "Galaxy Unification Wars", which desized his body, following his conquest.</description>
<picture>17610.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="601" picture="248145.jpg">Nakamura Hidetoshi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="6927" type="appears in" update="2009-05-18">
<rating votes="7">3.40</rating>
<name>Motemitsu Taizou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The best pitcher on the baseball team at Sainan High and an arrogant womaniser, whenever a new girl comes to the school, Motemitsu will try anything to get them to go on a date with him. Greatly admired by his teammates and the male student body, Motemitsu unfortunately is a closet pervert, having taken shots of girls changing. He also keeps a personal record of every girl in the school with him.</description>
<picture>25097.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="265" picture="25730.jpg">Namikawa Daisuke</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="11892" type="appears in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="57">7.61</rating>
<name>Magical Kyouko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A magical girl persona of http://anidb.net/ch11893 [Kirisaki Kyouko] which she portrays in her own show that http://anidb.net/ch2355 [Lala] and http://anidb.net/ch2354 [Rito] love watching.</description>
<picture>35991.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="540" picture="41046.jpg">Chiba Chiemi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="11893" type="appears in" update="2013-12-24">
<rating votes="72">8.16</rating>
<name>Kirisaki Kyouko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A half-Earthling half-alien girl, Kyouko is a famous idol which has the ability to create and throw fire at will and becomes a friend with http://anidb.net/ch2362 [Run] when Run portrays an antagonist on her show. She is best known for her role as http://anidb.net/ch11892 [Magical Kyouko], a fictional magical girl character who stars in her own television series that http://anidb.net/ch2355 [Lala] loves watching, often forcing http://anidb.net/ch2354 [Rito] to watch it with her. Kyouko is based on http://anidb.net/ch2440 [Kirisaki Kyouko] from http://anidb.net/a3321 [Black Cat]. Source: Wikipedia</description>
<picture>146729.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="540" picture="41046.jpg">Chiba Chiemi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="11895" type="appears in" update="2013-12-05">
<rating votes="3">7.04</rating>
<name>Shirone</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Shirone (a pun on shiro neko, white cat) serves as animal sidekick for http://anidb.net/ch11892 [Magical Kyouko] in her show. Is based on a http://anidb.net/ch11894 [similar character] from http://anidb.net/cr2985 [Yabuki Kentarou]`s other manga/anime series http://anidb.net/a3321 [Black Cat].</description>
<picture>146730.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3768" picture="188710.jpg">Hino Miho</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="25010" type="appears in" update="2010-11-11">
<rating votes="6">2.90</rating>
<name>Smutts</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Zastin`s assistant.</description>
<picture>59110.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3797" picture="65487.jpg">Matsuo Daisuke</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="25011" type="appears in" update="2010-11-11">
<rating votes="6">2.90</rating>
<name>Maul</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Zastin`s assistant.</description>
<picture>59111.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4741" picture="45560.jpg">Konno Jun</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="25153" type="appears in" update="2010-11-17">
<rating votes="6">2.55</rating>
<name>Honegawa-sensei</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>59421.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3064" picture="24692.jpg">Asou Tomohisa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="25844" type="appears in" update="2010-12-20">
<rating votes="13">5.55</rating>
<name>Marron</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>61098.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="65" picture="170428.jpg">Yoshino Hiroyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="26360" type="appears in" update="2011-01-02">
<rating votes="36">6.06</rating>
<name>Sairenji Akiho</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Haruna`s older sister, she shares her apartment with Haruna. Extremely popular with the guys (having received confessions from two men at the same time), Akiho continuously turns them down, as her sister states she is not looking for love at the moment. However, she has been dating Yuu Kotegawa.</description>
<picture>61857.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="216" picture="171983.jpg">Takahashi Mikako</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="67089" type="appears in" update="2014-04-29">
<rating votes="1">6.18</rating>
<name>Ghi Bree</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>155053.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="231" picture="23486.jpg">Madono Mitsuaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="67091" type="appears in" update="2014-04-30">
<name>Pikari</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Pikari is a Kirarian from a planet Kirara that is described as the State of Light. He is another one of Lala`s fiancé candidates. Source: To Love-ru wikia</description>
<picture>155055.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="233" picture="228661.jpg">Miki Shin`ichirou</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="67092" type="appears in" update="2014-04-30">
<rating votes="1">1.05</rating>
<name>Stella</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>155056.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1937" picture="92109.jpg">Aikawa Rikako</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="67093" type="appears in" update="2014-04-30">
<rating votes="1">6.18</rating>
<name>Lacospo</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Lacospo is a prince from the planet Gaama as well as one of Lala`s fiancé candidates and one of the few antagonists in the first series. He is by far the most persistent of Lala`s suitors and most recurring to try to win her love. Appearing multiple times in the manga to steal Lala, and even hired Konjiki no Yami and Ranjula to assassinate Yuuki Rito. Source: To Love-ru Wikia</description>
<picture>155059.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="254" picture="17073.jpg">Yamaguchi Kappei</seiyuu>
</character>
</characters>
<episodes>
<episode id="88794" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">1</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-04-04</airdate>
<rating votes="26">5.94</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">舞い降りた少女</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Girl Who Fell from the Sky</title>
<title xml:lang="fr">La fille qui tombait du ciel</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Maiorita Shoujo</title>
<summary>Rito is a shy boy just trying to get through life and pluck up the courage to confess his love to his long time school crush. Of course, the universe seems to be against him, even to the point of dropping a naked runaway alien princess named Lala quite literally into his lap and bathtub. As if things couldn`t get stranger, in the suds and confusion, Rito now finds himself engaged to the girl who fell from the sky. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>683483</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="89074" update="2008-03-31">
<epno type="4">T1</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">30 Second Commercial</title>
</episode>
<episode id="89826" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">2</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-04-11</airdate>
<rating votes="15">4.88</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">婚約解消!?</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Broken Engagement!?</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Konyaku Kaishou!?</title>
<summary>Things go from bad to worse for Rito.  First, he has a bunch of aliens show up, and then he finds that he`s engage to a galactic princess, now the girl he really likes is mad at him? How could things possibly get any worse? Oh, well, having Lala`s father blow up the earth would be pretty bad. Rito has only three days to set things right and prevent King Deviluke`s wrath over a broken engagement? Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684019</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="89877" update="2008-04-05">
<epno type="4">T2</epno>
<length>1</length>
<title xml:lang="en">Promo</title>
</episode>
<episode id="90031" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">3</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-04-18</airdate>
<rating votes="13">3.95</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">三角関係</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Love Triangle</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Sankaku Kankei</title>
<summary>Lala and all of this marriage stuff are driving Rito insane! At least he can catch a few hours of sanity alone at school.  What?!?! Lala is the new transfer student?! Even though Rito implores her to keep a low profile, her antics are making her rather popular.  Even worse, Haruna has just said that she thinks Rito and Lala make a good couple! In an attempt to cheer up Rito and teach Lala more about earth culture, Mikan decides they should go on a tour of the city.  Disaster is narrowly averted following a literal wardrobe malfunction and Lala`s inventions at the aquarium.  Oh, and Haruna ends up joining them on their outing which could be the beginning of a love triangle. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684021</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90255" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">4</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-04-25</airdate>
<rating votes="13">3.96</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">宇宙のLOVEエプロン</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Love Apron from Outer Space</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Uchuu no Love Apron</title>
<summary>Mikan is helping Lala feel right at home with delicious home cooked meals.  Her uncle Zastin, on the other hand, is not giving Rito a favorable idea of his future as the King of Deviluke, what with the waging of intergalactic wars and all.  Rito is desperate to find a way to get out of marrying Lala without attracting her father`s rage and being at fault for the destruction of the earth.  Inspired by Mikan`s hot meals, Lala tries to cook for the family, but as it`s her first time, the results are sub par.  Rito sees his chance and declares that he will not marry Lala unless she can cook well for him.  Oh course he`s wrong to think he just off scot-free, especially when Lala returns from a cross galactic grocery shopping trip, bound and determined don a love apron from outer space. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684023</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90353" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">6</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-05-09</airdate>
<rating votes="10">3.70</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">宇宙人の刺客</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Alien Assassin</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Uchuujin no Shikaku</title>
<summary>Lala seems to be really pushing Rito`s buttons at school.  All she wants to do is learn a bit more about him, but she may have gotten the wrong idea in science class when they were doing frog dissections.  Little does Rito know that he`s also being studied by another alien; this one a rival for Lala`s affection.  To get Rito to back off, this supposed assassin has taken Haruna hostage! Will this new guy finally get a clue that Lala is not interested in him? Can Rito save Haruna and himself from this intimidating alien assassin? Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684027</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90354" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">5</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-05-02</airdate>
<rating votes="12">5.45</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">くいーんの挑戦状</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Queen`s Challenge</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Queen no Chousenjou</title>
<summary>Saki Tenhouin is the queen of Sainan High School.  She`s the richest, the most popular, the prettiest, the vainest... you get the picture.  She`s also the most jealous of Lala when she finds out that her popularity is on the rise amongst the other students (due in part to her sex appeal).  But Miss Saki will not be out done! She challenges Lala to the Miss Sainan Competition.  However, it`s not a good idea to send an alien princess a challenge with an arrow stuck through it.  It`s an even worse idea to try to kidnap her fiancé to ensure that she shows up.  Refusing to be made a fool of, Saki will learn Lala`s secret and try to destroy her in the queen`s challenge.  If she can get out of the escape pod that is... Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684025</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90626" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">7</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-05-16</airdate>
<rating votes="13">3.59</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">男とはかくあるべし!</title>
<title xml:lang="en">All Men Should Be Like This</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Otoko to wa Kaku Arubeshi!</title>
<summary>A new rival has arrived at Sainan Private High School, Ren, one of Lala`s childhood friends.  Apparently, Ren has held Lala in such high regard that he allowed himself to be her guinea pig for experiments, was proud of the memories where she made him cry, and is not the least be upset that she doesn`t immediately remember him.  What is upsetting is that she still does not think of him as manly.  When they were young, Lala said that she would marry him if he became manly, but he still has a ways to go.  Not to be easily discouraged, Ren first turns to Rito for advice, then to the female students at school.  To prove his masculine strength and charm, Ren embarks upon a rigorous training regime, including fighting a gang leader and Big Foot before finally taking on a 120 km marathon.  Ren is so close to becoming the model of what all me should be like when- ... erm, gesundheit??? Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684029</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90766" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">8</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-05-23</airdate>
<rating votes="11">6.38</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">清廉潔白風紀委員</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Prefect of Spotless Integrety</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Seirenkeppaku Fuuki Iin</title>
<summary>One of the school prefects, Yui Kotegawa, is all about rules, discipline, and good morality.  She feels that things have gotten quite out of hand and will not tolerate anymore lewd behavior.  Yui convinces the principal to allow her to set some rules for moral behavior at school and creates an enforcement squad.  Rito comes under Yui’s special attention, as she suspects that he is the one behind the corruption of good and decent values.  As punishment, Rito is banned from speaking to any girl for two weeks!  With Lala and Ren causing all kinds of havoc, it seems almost impossible that Rito will be able to stay in line. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684031</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90810" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">12</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-06-20</airdate>
<rating votes="6">5.05</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">戦慄! 体育祭</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Frightening Field Day!</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Senritsu! Taiikusai</title>
<summary>The athletic festival has arrived and Rito is in the lead to making a complete fool of himself.  He’s trying everything he can think of to impress Haruna, but keeps accidentally bumping and touching her.  While Rito is pretty sure that Haruna absolutely hates him, Lala finds herself in competition with Saki, who still wants to beat her.  The only person who seems to be really enjoying themselves it the principal as he watches the female students go through bizarre and perverted contests. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684039</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90811" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">11</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-06-13</airdate>
<rating votes="9">7.70</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">金色の闇</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Golden Darkness</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Konjiki no Yami</title>
<summary>Rito encounters a golden haired girl on street.  They begin to talk and Rito buys them taiyuki when suddenly, she attacks!  It seems that both her hands and her golden locks are weapons.  Rito tries to run away, but she pursues him.  It turns out that she is an assassin, know as Golden Darkness, hired to kill him.  Zastin comes to rescue Rito, but this girl is more than he can handle.  Lala shows up, and the girl fight is on. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684037</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90812" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">10</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-06-06</airdate>
<rating votes="9">1.79</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">宇宙の女芸人......</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Space Entertainer</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Uchuu no Onna Geinin...</title>
<summary>Lala’s fan club president, Stella, shows up, trying to convince her to return to make an idol CD.  Stella becomes upset when she finds that Lala is engaged and refusing to go.  Rito is held responsible for this, and must find a stand in actress to pretend that she is Lala.  Rito becomes upset when Stella decides that Haruna would be the perfect double for Lala. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684035</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="90813" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">9</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-05-30</airdate>
<rating votes="12">4.35</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">光星より愛を込めて</title>
<title xml:lang="en">From a Shining Star, with Love</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kousei yori Ai o Komete</title>
<summary>Another suitor blasts his way into the picture, this time quite literally, as he wears an armored rocket suit.  He decided to cut straight to the point and keeps trying to snatch Lala.  Lala is able to dodge his attacks, but she finally get frustrated and fights back.  Wounded and with his armor damaged, he wander about, seeking advice from everyone, even Ren.  He comes up with a new plan to claim Lala and attempts to drug her. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684033</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="91229" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">13</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-06-27</airdate>
<rating votes="7">5.34</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">宇宙一の男</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Greatest Man in the Universe</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Uchuuichi no Otoko</title>
<summary>Rito is about to have the worse ‘meet the parent’ experience in the whole universe! Lala’s father, King Deviluke is coming to earth to see if Rito is worthy of being his daughter’s future husband and eventual ruler of their planet.  At school, Rito meets a strange girl on the roof, who turns out to be Lala’s father testing him.  Having made a very bad first impression, it looks like Rito is about to learn about intergalactic pain, until Lala steps in.  Now, Rito is left with only one option to save himself and the earth from total destruction: become the Greatest Man in the Universe. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684041</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="91578" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">14</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-04</airdate>
<rating votes="9">6.16</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ふたりだけの秘密</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Secret Between the Two of Us</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Futari Dake no Himitsu</title>
<summary>Rito is training hard to hopefully become the Greatest Man in the Universe and save his life in the process.  While out running, he bumps into Haruna walking her dog.  She becomes very supportive of Rito, even meeting up with him everyday as he runs.  Finally, Haruna asks Rito to have lunch with her by the river.  During their date, her dog falls into the water and is rescued by Rito.  Dripping wet, Haruna takes him to her house to dry his clothes.  There, Haruna trips and almost kisses a towel-clad Rito just as her sister enters the room. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684043</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="91683" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">15</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-11</airdate>
<rating votes="8">6.95</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">密林のプリンセス</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Princess of the Jungle</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Mitsurin no Princess</title>
<summary>Rito, Haruna, and Lala are moving up in the universe, when an alien prince visits and they each become Ambassadors of Peace from the Earth.  They get more than just their titles, but a challenge to compete for the title of Greatest Hunter in the Universe.  This could be a big opportunity for Rito in reaching his goal of become the greatest man, so they compete.  After an adventure filled with dinosaurs and giant gorillas, Haruna wins the title, while Rito finds a group of Amazons who want to all marry him. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684045</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92021" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">16</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-18</airdate>
<rating votes="8">4.94</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ルンの突撃告白タイム</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Run`s Surprise Confession</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Run no Totsugeki Kokuhaku Time</title>
<summary>Everyone decides to have a fun afternoon together at the water park.  However, Rito now has a new source of relationship drama: Run has fallen in love with him, too.  Through their whole afternoon, she tries everything she can imagine to get Rito’s attention.  From fishing poles to vacuums and even fabric-eating fish, each of her attempts ends in disaster for Rito.  She finally gets some advice from Montemitsu and Rito’s teacher, but finds herself in a spot of trouble with the other patrons of the park.  Rito steps in to help her and Lala whips out one of her new inventions.  Unfortunately for Rito, this is only the beginning of Run’s campaign for his affection. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684047</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92036" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">17</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-07-25</airdate>
<rating votes="9">4.76</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">旧校舎の幽霊</title>
<title xml:lang="en">The Ghost in the Old School Building</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Kyuu Kousha no Yuurei</title>
<summary>Rito and everyone decide to go to the old school building to find out if the rumor of a ghost haunting the building is true. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684049</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92085" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">18</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-01</airdate>
<rating votes="8">2.42</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">猿山がお土産</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Saruyama, the Gift</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Saruyama ga Omiyage</title>
<summary>A space ship flies over the school and drops off a package for Lala on the roof. Inside the package is a pregnant wolf that jumps out and tries to kill Lala. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684051</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92224" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">19</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-08</airdate>
<rating votes="7">4.00</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">地獄温泉女宇宙人七色ポロリ</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Hell`s Hot Springs: Alien Girls and Colorful Exposed Bodies</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Jigoku Onsen Onna Uchuujin Nanairo Porori</title>
<summary>After seeing a commercial on TV promoting a hot springs, Lala tells Rito that she wants to own a hot springs. Lala then proceeds to build her own hot springs right in her own backyard. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684053</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92225" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">20</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-15</airdate>
<rating votes="19">1.41</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">爆熱少女マジカルキョーコ炎(フレイム)</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Explosive Heat Magical Girl Kyouko Flame</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Bakunetsu Shoujo Magical Kyouko Flame</title>
<summary>General Mojack decides to try and take over the world so Kirisaki takes it upon her self to destroy him by turning into Magical Kyoko Flame. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684055</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92226" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">21</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-22</airdate>
<rating votes="8">4.52</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">結城亭血風録</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Chronicle of Bloodshed at Yuuki Inn</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Yuuki Tei Keppuuroku</title>
<summary>Yuuki hears about an alien hotel being run by Mikade-sensei and Kimio. There Yuuki decides to try it check it out via the old school building. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684057</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92227" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">22</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-08-29</airdate>
<rating votes="6">7.36</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">戦慄! 文化祭</title>
<title xml:lang="en">A Frightening School Festival!</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Senritsu! Bunkasai</title>
<summary>Everyone is upset by Yui`s submission of what they should do for the culture festival. She submitted that they do a region research display or a calligraphy display. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684059</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92505" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">23</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-05</airdate>
<rating votes="10">1.80</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">猿山の大奥物語</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Saruyama`s Tales of the Inner Chambers</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Saruyama no Oooku Monogatari</title>
<summary>Saruyama wishes that he was a nobleman from the Edo Castle. He then starts to daydream about being the ruler of Edo Castle. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684061</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92506" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">24</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-12</airdate>
<rating votes="6">7.83</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">はじらいながら</title>
<title xml:lang="en">With Shyness</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Hajirai Nagara</title>
<summary>Lala`s personality changes due to a fever. Rito now has to deal with Lala`s constantly changing personalitues and her desire to take over the world as a deviluke princess. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684063</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92930" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">26</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-26</airdate>
<rating votes="10">4.51</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">ララ</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Lala</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Lala</title>
<summary>Yuki wakes up to Haruna and Lala yelling at him that he is about to miss the ship. Lala decides she can`t marry unless he wants too. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684067</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="92931" update="2017-01-04">
<epno type="1">25</epno>
<length>25</length>
<airdate>2008-09-19</airdate>
<rating votes="7">7.67</rating>
<title xml:lang="ja">地球最後の夜</title>
<title xml:lang="en">Earth`s Final Night</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat">Chikyuu Saigo no Yoru</title>
<summary>Rito receives a message from the King of Deviluke which orders him to board the Devilukian spaceship as he has to prove he is the best in the universe. Before boarding the ship he confesses his feelings for Haruna. Source: crunchyroll</summary>
<resources>
<resource type="28">
<externalentity>
<identifier>684065</identifier>
<identifier>to-love-ru</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
</episode>
<episode id="93103" update="2010-06-25">
<epno type="3">C1</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2008-04-04</airdate>
<rating votes="1">10.00</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Opening</title>
</episode>
<episode id="93104" update="2010-04-12">
<epno type="3">C2</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2008-04-04</airdate>
<rating votes="1">8.12</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 1</title>
</episode>
<episode id="95132" update="2010-04-12">
<epno type="3">C3</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2008-07-04</airdate>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 2</title>
</episode>
<episode id="122323" update="2010-09-13">
<epno type="3">C4</epno>
<length>2</length>
<airdate>2008-09-26</airdate>
<title xml:lang="en">Ending 3</title>
</episode>
</episodes>
</anime>
